在本节中，我们将研究计算正交旋转矩阵的导数。
In this section we're going to look at computing the derivative of an orthogonal rotation matrix.
正交矩阵的一个特性是它的倒数等于它的转置
One of the properties of an orthogonal matrix is that it's inverse is equal to its transpose
所以我们可以写出这个简单的关系R次，它的转置必须等于单位矩阵。
so we can write this simple relationship R times it's transpose must be equal to the identity matrix.
首先，我将考虑通过角度θ旋转的简单情况
First off I'm going to consider the simple case of a rotation by the angle theta about
X轴。我可以采用关于theta的衍生物并使用链规则
the X-axis. I can take the derivative with respect to theta and using the chain rule
我可以写这个。应用此身份我可以用这种特殊的形式重写它
I can write this. Applying this identity I can rewrite it in this particular form and
我可以通过引入符号S来表示此表达式来简化它。
I can simplify it by introducing the symbol S to represent this expression here.
矩阵S具有一个有趣的属性。如果我将它添加到它的转置，结果将会
The matrix S has an interesting property. If I add it to its transpose the result will
等于零。并且这种矩阵被称为偏斜对称矩阵。
be equal to zero. And this kind of matrix is referred to as a skew-symmetric matrix.
偏斜对称矩阵的性质也可以这样写。所以这种
That property of the skew-symmetric matrix can also be written like this. So this kind
矩阵的有时也被称为反对称矩阵。
of matrix is also sometimes referred to as an anti-symmetric matrix.
这些矩阵总是单数的，它确定总是等于零。
These matrices are always singular that is that it determines is always equal to zero.
任何矩阵都可以写成对称矩阵和斜对称矩阵之和。
Any matrix can be written as the sum of a symmetric matrix and a skew-symmetric matrix.
在三维中，斜对称矩阵具有这种形式。它有一个非常独特的
In three dimensions the skew-symmetric matrix has this form. It's got a very distinctive
零对角线，此矩阵x，y，z和每个矩阵中只有三个独特的元素
zero diagonal and there are only three unique elements in this matrix x, y, z and each of
它们带有正号和负号。现在有趣的特点了
them appears with a positive sign and a negative sign. Now the interesting characteristic of
斜对称矩阵是一种编写向量叉积关系的方法
the skew-symmetric matrix is it’s a way to write the vector cross product relationship
作为从矢量A乘以的矢量计算的斜对称矩阵的乘积
as the product of a skew-symmetric matrix computed from the vector A multiplied by the
矢量B.因此，交叉积可以变成矩阵矢量积。
vector B. So cross product can be turned into a matrix vector product.
这是S的早期表达式，我可以写下矩阵的表达式
Here's our earlier expression for S and I can write down an expression for a matrix
它表示围绕X轴旋转角度θ。如果我替换这些
which represents rotation about the X axis by the angle theta. If I substitute these
值，并简化我最终得到一个包含很多零的非常简单的矩阵
values in, and simplify I end up with a very simple matrix containing a lot of zeroes one
还有一个。回顾我们早期的表达式，即对称矩阵这个矩阵
and a minus one. Recalling our earlier expression for a skew-symmetric matrix this matrix that
我刚刚写下来，我可以写为矢量[100]的偏斜对称矩阵。所以
I've just written down I can write as a skew- symmetric matrix of the vector [1 0 0]. So the
相对于θ的旋转矩阵的导数由偏斜的乘积给出-
derivative of a rotation matrix with respect to theta is given by the product of a skew-
对称矩阵乘以原始旋转矩阵。
symmetric matrix multiplied by the original rotation matrix.
我可以执行代数操作，围绕Y轴旋转，也可以
I can perform the algebraic manipulation for a rotation around the Y axis and also for
围绕Z轴旋转，我在这里得到这些表达式，你可以清楚地看到一些
a rotation around the Z axis and I get these expressions here and you can clearly see some
一种模式。现在让我们考虑一般情况。关于向量L的旋转
kind of pattern. Now let's consider the general case. A rotation about the vector L by an
角θ和它可以表明这等于斜对称的乘积
angle theta and it can be shown that this is equal to the product of a skew-symmetric
从矢量L乘以原始旋转矩阵计算的矩阵。
matrix computed from the vector L multiplied by the original rotation matrix.
如果我现在将表达式的两边乘以deethetadeeT，那就是theta的变化率，
If I now multiply both sides of the expression by dee theta dee T, that's the rate of change of theta,
我可以写一个这样的表达式。
I can write an expression like this.
这是什么，是一般旋转矩阵的时间导数。
What this is, is a time derivative of a general rotation matrix.
围绕向量L的θ的旋转等于计算的偏斜对称矩阵
A rotation of theta about the vector L is equal to a skew-symmetric matrix computed
在矢量Omega乘以原始旋转矩阵。
on the vector Omega multiplied by the original rotational matrix.
在这种情况下，欧米茄是角速度矢量。它是角度的变化率
Omega in this case is the angular velocity vector. It is the rate of change of angle
乘以旋转发生的矢量方向。
multiplied by the vector direction about which the rotation is occurring.